这应该能制成不错的样本
That should make a good specimen.
开始降温了
Temperature's starting to drop.
是啊
Yeah.
晚上能降到零下120度
At night it gets down to 120 degrees below zero.
鸡皮疙瘩能冻掉一地
That's nippy.
- 怎么了？ - 从上面摔了下来，长官
- What happened? - Fell off that bank, sir.
- 手被割破了 - 让我瞧瞧
- Cut my hand. - Let's see.
返回星舰，去医务室报道
Get back to the ship. Report to the Sickbay.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
地质员费舍尔，准备传送
Geological Technician Fisher, ready to beam up.
好的，已经锁定你了
Right. Locked onto you.
传送
Energize.
校正器开启
Coadjutor engagement.
- 怎么啦？ - 我摔了一跤
- What happened? - I took a flop.
- 跌到什么东西上了？ - 不知道
- Onto what? - I don't know.
- 像是某种黄色矿砂 - 有磁性
- Some kind of yellow ore. - Magnetic.
- 得净化这身衣服 - 是，长官
- Decontaminate that uniform. - Yes, sir.
像是燃料烧尽的样子
That acted like a burnout.
我是寇克，准备传送
Captain Kirk, ready to beam up.
稍等，舰长
Just one moment, captain.
现在又好了
It checks out okay now.
去拿同步测量仪，这样就能复核了
You better go get a synchronic meter so we can double-check.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
好啦，舰长，锁定你了
All right, captain. Locked onto you.
- 没事吧，舰长？ - 没事，就是有点晕
- Are you all right, captain? - It's all right. I’m just a little dizzy.
- 小心，让我来扶你 - 我也穿不过去啊
- Here, let me give you a hand. - I can't get through there.
不碍事，传送室必须有人值守
Nothing serious. Don't leave the transporter room unattended.
威尔森马上就回来，长官
Wilson will be right back, sir.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：kmdangdangli 土豆爱 Nick
校对：心痕依 Micezhang xjCGI
第一季第五集
心中之敌
舰长日志，星历1672.1
Captain's log, stardate 1672.1.
阿尔法177号行星，样本采集任务
Specimen-gathering mission on planet Alfa 177.
那时还没人知道
Unknown to any of us during this time,
因传送器故障，复制出
a duplicate of me, some strange alter ego,
另一个我，性情相反的我
had been created by the transporter malfunction.
舰长，你没事吧，长官？
Captain, are you all right, sir?
需要帮忙吗，长官？
Can I give you a hand, sir?
舰长？
Captain?
呼叫各部门，请检查通讯线路
Section to the officers. Please check communication lines.
多谢
Thank you.
最好还是让麦考伊医生好好查查
It might profit you to let Dr. McCoy give you the once-over.
知道啦，轮机长，我会去查查这身“零件”
All right, engineer, I'll have my engines looked to.
长官，这是清单
Ship's manifests, sir.
- 都整理好了 - 谢谢你，文书
- They're in order now. - Thank you, yeoman.
- 我已经检查… - 就这样吧
- I've checked-- - That's all.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
你可真会挑日子，费舍尔
You picked a good day, Fisher.
最近任务有点脏兮兮，你就
Business has been lousy. What did you do,
故意摔个跤，偷个小懒吗？
take a fall on purpose so you could get a little vacation?
蜥蜴白兰地
Saurian brandy.
回去干活吧，费舍尔
Back to duty status, Fisher.
我可不会同情你笨手笨脚的
I have no sympathy for clumsiness.
是，长官
No, sir.
我的手好多了，长官
The hand's much better, sir.
- 有何指示，吉姆？ - 我都说了要白兰地！
- What can I do for you, Jim? - I said give me the brandy!
（文书贾尼丝·兰德）
- 谁啊？ - 史波克
- Yeah? - Mr. Spock.
请进
Come in.
有事吗，史波克？
Yes, Mr. Spock, what is it?
需要我做什么吗，舰长？
Is there something I can do for you, captain?
比如？
Like what?
麦考伊医生让我过来看看你
Well, Dr. McCoy seemed to think that I should check on you.
他心肠真好
That's nice.
好了，史波克，你的眼神瞒不了我
Come on, Spock, I know that look.
怎么了？
What is it?
嗯…我们好心的医生说
Well, our good doctor said
你举止粗暴，像个野人
that you were acting like a wild man.
吵着要喝白兰地
Demanded brandy.
这位好好医生又拿你开涮啦
Our good doctor's been putting you on again.
既然如此，我便不打扰了，舰长
Well, in that case, if you'll excuse the intrusion, captain,
我这就回去做事
I'll get back to my work.
我会转告他，你被气得够呛
I'll tell him you were properly annoyed.
舰长
Captain.
- 什么事，史考特？ - 传送器坏了，长官
- What is it, Scotty? - Transporter breakdown, sir.
还在检查电路
Continue circuit testing.
我们传送的是这只
We beamed up this animal,
你自己再看看样本箱的
and well, look for yourself. It's in this specimen case.
- 怎么回事？ - 传送器刚把
- Yes? - A few seconds
这只送上来，几秒钟后
after they sent this one up through the transporter,
那只复制品跑了出来，不能说一模一样
that duplicate appeared, except it's not a duplicate.
二者性情相反，长得一样，但又不同
It's an opposite. Two of the same animal but different.
一个温驯，这只
One gentle, this:
一个凶悍，那只
One mean and fierce, that:
异常凶猛野蛮
Some kind of savage, ferocious opposite.
舰长
Captain,
绝不能传送苏鲁和外遣队上来
we don't dare send Mr. Sulu and the landing party up.
如果这发生在人身上…
If this should happen to a man.
噢…我的天！
Oh, my--
喔…舰长，你吓我一跳
Oh, captain, you startled me.
你有何…？
Is there something that you--?
找我有事吗，舰长？
Can I help you, captain?
现在叫我吉姆，贾尼丝
"Jim" will do here, Janice.
你美得让人无法忽视
You're too beautiful to ignore.
太美了
Too much woman.
我们一直都…
We've both been...
伪装的太久了
...pretending too long.
别再装了
Stop pretending.
我们都别装了
Let's stop pretending.
来吧，贾尼丝，别抗拒我
Come here, Janice. Don't fight me.
别再抗拒了，贾尼丝
Don't fight me, Janice.
住手
I can't.
就一会儿，贾尼丝
Just a minute, Janice.
就一会儿！
Just a minute!
快叫史波克！快叫史波克！
Call Mr. Spock! Call Mr. Spock!
我是地质员费舍尔
Geological Technician Fisher.
我在12号甲板，部门…
Deck 12, section--
我？
Me?
我的文书亲口说的？
My yeoman said that?
你走后，我就在这里休息，就一个人，史波克
I've been resting here since you left me. Alone, Mr. Spock.
舰长，麦考伊医生说
Captain, Dr. McCoy reports
这瓶白兰地是你在医务室拿的
that you demanded this brandy in Sickbay and left with it.
我在文书兰德的舱室找到了这瓶酒
I found this bottle in Yeoman Rand's quarters.
胡说，我压根就没去医务室
Not true. I haven't been to the Sickbay.
还是去查个水落石出吧
Let's find out what's going on.
医务室
Sickbay.
接着他就强吻我，然后说我们…
And then he kissed me and he said that we--
他是舰长
That he was the captain.
我又不能抗命…
That he could order me...
当时我手足无措
I didn't know what to do.
然后提及我们彼此隐藏的感情
Then you mentioned the feelings we've been hiding,
- 接着开始说我们的事 - 我们？
- and you started talking about us. - Us?
是“你和我”…
Well, we...
他是舰长
He is the captain.
我总不能…
I couldn't just...
你紧紧按住我
You started hurting me.
我只有还击，抓伤了你的脸
I had to fight you, scratch your face.
- 文书 - 然后…
- Yeoman. - And...
看着我
Look at me.
看着我，看我的脸
Look at me. Look at my face.
上面有抓痕吗？
Are there any scratches?
我敢肯定我抓伤你了
I was sure I scratched you.
当时我很害怕，也许…
I was frightened. Maybe--
文书，我一直在我的房间，那个人不是我
Yeoman, I was in my room. It wasn't me.
长官，费舍尔也看到你了
Sir, Fisher saw you too.
费舍尔也…
Fisher saw...
要不是…
If it hadn't been...
我清楚自己的身份
I can understand.
所以不想给你添乱
I don't wanna get you into trouble.
本想只字不提
I wouldn't have even mentioned it.
- 不是我干的 - 就是你，长官
- It wasn't me. - It was you, sir.
- 你知道你在说什么吗？ - 是，我知道
- Do you know what you're saying? - Yes, I know what I'm saying.
回去躺着吧，傻小子，走吧，我们走
Back to that bed, bucko. Come on, let's go.
你可以走了，文书
You can go now, yeoman.
唯一合理的解释
There's only one logical answer.
这里有个冒名顶替者
We have an impostor aboard.
舰长日志，星历1672.9
Captain's log, stardate 1672.9.
行星地面温度开始下降
On the planet's surface, temperatures are beginning to drop.
外遣队处境危险
Our landing party there in growing jeopardy.
因为传送器的故障
Due to the malfunction of the ship's transporter,
我的一个复制品离奇般来到星舰
an unexplained duplicate of myself definitely exists.
- 这到底怎么回事？ - 我也不清楚，长官
- How did all this happen? - I don't know, sir.
但费舍尔登舰时衣服上有层松软的黄色矿砂
But when Fisher came up, his suit was covered with a soft yellow ore.
属性极其罕见
It had highly unusual properties.
估计导致了超载，但还不确定
It may have caused an overload. I can't tell. Not yet.
- 传送器还能用吗？ - 还能，长官
- Does the transporter work at all? - Yes, sir.
但不能冒险传送外遣队员
But we don't dare bring up the landing party.
可能会出现分裂，就像这只动物
They might be duplicated like this animal.
多久才能搞定这个故障？
How long will it take you to find the trouble?
不好说，长官
Can't say, sir.
不能把那四个人丢在下面
We just can't leave those four men down there.
天一黑，他们都会死
It's getting dark, they'll die.
晚上地面温度只有零下120度
The temperature of that planet goes down to 120 degrees below zero.
我们正全力以赴，长官
We're doing everything we can, sir.
好，我知道了，史考特
Yes, I know, Scotty.
至于你的“孪生兄弟”，舰长？
About your double, captain.
哦…是啊
Yes.
必须找到他，搜查队，史波克，组织搜查队
We'll have to find him. Search parties, Mr. Spock. Organize search parties.
我们不能冒险杀害他
We can't take a chance on killing it.
我们还不清楚
We have no previous experience,
是否对你会有影响
no way of knowing what would happen to you.
是啊，是的，我们还不知道
Yes, that's right. We don't know.
但还是让大家准备武器
But the men have to be armed.
必须配备武器，但相位枪必须锁定为…
The men are to be armed, but their phasers locked--
模式一，切记【该模式只能击晕对方】
I repeat, locked on setting number one.
一定不能杀害他
There can't be any chance of him being killed.
拿下他必须无…
He's to be taken without...
如果他反抗引发交火…
If the men are forced to fire,
还是不能杀害他
he can't be killed.
那该如何解释，舰长？
How shall we explain it to them, captain?
直接叫搜查队去抓你？
That the search parties are to capture you?
就说…
Tell them...
搜查队，舰长
The search parties, captain.
哦…我会向全体船员说明
Yes, I’ll make an announcement to the entire crew.
事情的来龙去脉
Tell them what happened.
他们都是好船员，他们有知情权
It's a good crew. They deserve to know.
舰长，恕我直言
Captain, no disrespect intended,
无论如何你都不能透露事实真相
but you must surely realize you can't announce the full truth to the crew.
你是一舰之长，你不能在所有
You're the captain of this ship. You haven't the right
船员面前暴露自己脆弱的一面
to be vulnerable in the eyes of the crew.
你只能做个十全十美的舰长
You can't afford the luxury of being anything less than perfect.
否则，他们会对你失去信念，没人会听你的命令
If you do, they lose faith and you lose command.
这点我很清楚，史波克
Yes, I do know that, Mr. Spock.
我只是不明白…
What I don't know...
为什么刚才我把这点忘记了？
...is why I forgot that just now.
史波克…
Mr. Spock...
下次我若再有迟疑，你可要…
...if you see me slipping again, your orders...
你可得…
Your orders...
提醒我
...are to tell me.
明白，舰长
Understood, captain.
舰长日志，星历1673.1
Captain's log, stardate 1673.1.
我出了一些状况
Something has happened to me.
不知何故，我被复制了
Somehow, in being duplicated,
我失去了意志力
I have lost my strength of will.
果断做出决定变得愈发困难
Decisions are becoming more and more difficult.
这里是舰长讲话
This is the captain speaking.
本舰现有一个冒名顶替者
There's an impostor aboard the ship.
他与我极其相似，并伪装成我
A man who looks exactly like me and is pretending to be me.
这个人很危险，大家要保持高度警惕
This man is dangerous. Utmost caution is to be observed.
全体船员武装自卫
All crew members are to arm themselves.
冒名者或可通过脸上的抓痕进行识别
The impostor may be identified by scratches on his face.
重复一遍，冒名者或可通过
Repeat, the impostor may be identified
脸上的抓痕进行识别
by scratches on his face.
各部门主管
Section chiefs,
指定专人进行搜查
assign personnel to the search.
全体搜查队向史波克大副报到并等待任务分配
All search parties report to Mr. Spock for assignment.
- 有事？ - 相位枪
- Something? - About the phaser weapons
应该锁定为击晕模式
to be set for stunning force and locked.
哦，是啊，是啊
Oh, yes, yes.
所有相位枪必须设为
All hand phasers must be set
基础的击晕模式
on base cycle stunning force.
不要伤害冒名者，尽量不要使用武力
The impostor is not to be injured. Use minimum force.
- 重复一遍，不要伤害… - 我是寇克舰长！
- Repeat, the impostor - I'm Captain Kirk!
冒名者
is not to be injured.
我才是寇克舰长
I'm Captain Kirk.
我才是寇克舰长！
I'm Captain Kirk!
我才是寇克舰长
I'm Captain Kirk.
- 威尔森 - 长官？
- Wilson. - Sir?
威尔森，把你的相位枪给我
Wilson, give me your phaser.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
- 你最近怎么样？ - 很好，长官
- How you been? - Fine, sir.
下面进展如何，苏鲁先生？
How's it going down there, Mr. Sulu?
已经零下20度了
It's already 20 degrees below zero.
应该算不上暖和吧
Can't exactly call it balmy.
怎么才能帮他们一把呢？
Isn't there any way we can help them?
加热器已经传送下去了，但也被复制了
Thermo-heaters were transported down. They duplicated.
无法正常运转
They won't operate.
我们必须把这些人传送上来
Then we've got to get those men up.
- 史波克先生？ - 我是史波克
- Mr. Spock? - Spock here.
在舰长舱房附近发现传送技术官威尔森受伤
Transporter Technician Wilson found injured near the captain's cabin.
他说是冒名者袭击了他
He says the impostor attacked him,
叫出了他的名字并拿走了他的相位枪
called him by name, took his hand phaser.
收到，继续搜查
Acknowledged. Continue the search.
我们必须尽快找到他
We've got to find him before he--
但怎么找呢？
But how?
显然，这个复制品
Apparently, this double,
虽然性情和你不同，但却一样对本舰…
however different in temperament, has your knowledge of the ship,
对船员、设备都了如指掌
its crew, its devices.
既然如此，也许我们能够通过
This being the case, perhaps we can outguess him
预测他的下一部动作而智取他
by determining his next move.
清楚了解星舰布局
Knowing how the ship is laid out,
你会躲到哪里避开大搜捕呢？
where would you go to elude a mass search?
底层
The lower levels.
轮机甲板层
The engineering deck.
锁定为基础击晕档，不致命
Set and locked on base cycle to stun, not to kill.
你的相位枪呢，舰长？
What about your phaser, captain?
我们是不是叫些援手过来，舰长？
Don't you think we ought to get some help, captain?
不用
No.
我不想让其他人看到我
I don't want anyone else to see me.
舰长，你下达过命令要我提醒你…
Captain, you ordered me to tell you--
史波克先生…
Mr. Spock...
只要我还是舰长…
...if I'm to be the captain...
我就得表现的像个舰长
...I've gotta act like one.
你不能伤害我
You can't hurt me.
不能杀我
You can't kill me.
你不能，不明白吗？
You can't. Don't you understand?
我是你的一部分
I'm part of you.
你需要我
You need me.
我需要你
I need you.
我不需要你
I don't need you.
他马上就能恢复意识
He'll be regaining consciousness soon,
因为不知道他的身体状况
and not knowing what his physical state is,
什么镇静剂我都不敢给他用
I don't think I dare give him a tranquilizer of any kind.
我想最好还是绑着他
I think we better bind him.
好的
Yes.
好的，没问题
Yes, all right.
我这是怎么了？
What's the matter with me?
舰长，依我判断
Judging from my observations, captain,
你正在迅速失去决策力
you're rapidly losing the power of decision.
你有什么想法，史波克？
You have a point, Spock?
是，一向如此，医生
Yes. Always, doctor.
现在你拥有一个不寻常的机会来鉴定人类的思维
You have here an unusual opportunity to appraise the human mind,
按地球术语来讲，就是可以检验一个人的好与坏
or to examine, in Earth terms, the roles of good and evil in a man.
他的阴暗面，也就是你们所说的敌意、欲望、暴力
His negative side, which you call hostility, lust, violence.
还有他好的一面
And his positive side,
就是地球人所表达的怜悯
which Earth people express as compassion,
爱、温柔
love, tenderness.
你知道你是在分析舰长的内在吗，史波克？
It's the captain's guts you're analyzing. Are you aware of that, Spock?
是啊，是什么让一个人成为杰出领袖呢？
Yes. And what is it that makes one man an exceptional leader?
现在看来，他的阴暗面恰恰使他强大
We see here indications that it is his negative side which makes him strong.
适当的控制和约束他的阴暗面
That his evil side, if you will, properly controlled and disciplined,
促使了他的强大
is vital to his strength.
阴暗面从你身上剥离
Your negative side, removed from you,
决策力就开始远离你
the power of command begins to elude you.
你想说明什么，史波克先生？
What is your point, Mr. Spock?
如果你的决策力持续减弱的话
If your power of command continues to weaken,
就无法胜任舰长一职
you'll soon be unable to function as captain.
你必须做好准备
You must be prepared for that.
你有智慧，吉姆，你可以与之斗争
You have your intellect, Jim. You can fight with that.
斗争多久？
For how long?
舰长，如果我对你所遭遇的一切表现的不甚理解
If I seem insensitive to what you're going through, captain,
请理解，这就是我的方式
understand, it's the way I am.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk.
- 我是寇克 - 我是史考特，长官
- Kirk here. - Mr. Scott, sir,
现在正在底层轮机甲板层
on the lower level of the engineering deck.
我发现传送器又有了新问题
I found a new trouble with the transporter.
套管被撕裂了一个大口
The casing has a wide gap ripped in it.
主线路已经完全烧毁
The main circuits have been burned through.
中断控制回路都搭到了一起
The abort control circuit is gone altogether.
舰长，能否给我们一个进度报告？
Can you give us a status report, captain?
温度仍在下降
Temperature's still dropping.
现在是零下41摄氏度
Now 41 degrees below zero.
我们已经找到问题所在，不会耽搁太久
we've located the trouble. It shouldn't be much longer.
你能否找到一根长绳
Do you think you might be able to find a long rope somewhere
吊一壶热咖啡下来给我们？
and lower us down a pot of hot coffee?
我看看我们能做些什么
I'll see what we can do.
如果咖啡不够的话米酒也行阿
Rice wine will do if you're short on coffee.
轮机甲板层，我是寇克
Engineering deck, Kirk here.
我是史考特，舰长
Scott here, captain.
史考特，报告进程
That unit, Scotty, status report.
传送机离子发生器毁坏殆尽，长官
The transporter unit ionizer, nothing much left of it, sir.
有多糟？
How bad is it?
要修好的话至少一个星期
we can't repair it in less than a week.
舰长日志，星历1673.5
Captain's log, stardate 1673.5.
传送器仍然失灵
Transporter still inoperable.
我的阴暗面被软禁在医务室
My negative self is under restraint in sickbay,
我愈发的优柔寡断
my own indecisiveness growing.
意志力却逐步减弱
My force of will steadily weakening.
而行星上，情况严峻
On the planet, condition critical.
地表温度零下75度，并且持续下降
Surface temperature is 75 degrees below zero, still dropping.
我想我们该再次呼叫下客房服务了
I think we ought to give room service another call.
沏咖啡的时间太长了
That coffee's taking too long.
进取号，我是苏鲁
Enterprise, this is Sulu.
我是寇克，苏鲁先生
Kirk here, Mr. Sulu.
热线直呼舰长，我们错过什么了？
Hotline direct to the captain. Are we that far gone?
我让大家下午放假了，我自己看店呢
I gave everybody the afternoon off. I'm watching the store.
- 下边怎么样了？ - 哦，很美妙
- How is it down there? - Oh, lovely,
只是到处都挂满了冰霜
except that the frost is building up.
我们正用相位枪加热岩石
We're using hand phasers to heat the rocks.
一把相位枪失效了，还有三个可以操作
One phaser quit on us, three still operating.
能不能在滑雪季到来前
Any possibility of getting us back aboard
把我们弄回星舰？
before the skiing season opens down here?
我是史波克，苏鲁先生
This is Spock, Mr. Sulu.
你们必须再多坚持一下，没其他办法了
You'll have to hold on a little longer. There's no other way.
苏鲁先生，现在启动野外生存程序
Survival procedures, Mr. Sulu.
谨遵您的训练计划，史波克先生
Per your training program, Mr. Spock.
- 怎么回事？ - 很显然，身体功能
- What happened? - Apparently, the body functioning
在复制过程中变弱
weakened during the duplication process.
我没想到会这样
A fact I failed to consider.
他不会死的
He's not dying.
不，他就要死了
Yes, he is.
救救我
Help me.
他怎么能死呢？
How can he die?
- 没有他我怎么活？ - 我不知道，吉姆
- How can I survive without him? - I don't know, Jim.
别怕
Don't be afraid.
我的手在这
Here's my hand.
坚持住
Hold on.
你不用害怕，我不会不管你的
You don't have to be afraid. I won't let go.
坚持住，别害怕，用你的大脑去思考
Hold on. You won't be afraid if you use your mind and think.
思考，你能做到，就是这样
Think, you can do it. That's it.
吉姆，他缓过来了
Jim, he is back.
吉姆…
Jim...
…你现在可以去喝那瓶白兰地了
...you can use that brandy now.
- 实际上，我要和你一起喝 - 我必须把他救回来
- In fact, I'll join you. - I have to take him back
和我融合
inside myself.
没有他我活不下去，其实我不想他回来
I can't survive without him. I don't wanna take him back.
他就像个禽兽，没有思想的残暴禽兽
He's like an animal, a thoughtless brutal animal.
然而，那就是我
And yet, it's me.
我
Me.
吉姆…
Jim...
…你和别人没有什么区别
...you're no different than anyone else.
我们都有黑暗的一面，我们需要那一面
We all have our darker side. We need it.
那是我们的一半
It's half of what we are.
- 那并不丑陋，那就是人类 - 人类？
- It's not really ugly, it's human. - Human?
是啊，人类
Yes, human.
是那一部分使你成为了这样的人
Part of what he is makes you the man you are.
我真不愿意认同史波克的想法，可他是对的
God forbid I should have to agree with Spock, but he was right.
没有了阴暗面，你不可能成为舰长的
Without the negative side, you wouldn't be the captain.
你不可能，你知道的
You couldn't be and you know it.
你的决策力大多依赖于他
Your strength of command lies mostly in him.
- 我还剩下什么？ - 你还有善良
- What do I have? - You have the goodness.
不够，我有一艘星舰要指挥
Not enough. I have a ship to command.
智慧、逻辑，看来你现在这一半拥有这些优点
The intelligence, the logic. It appears your half has most of that.
也许这就是一个人勇气力量的源泉
And perhaps that's where man's essential courage comes from.
你看
For you see,
他害怕，你却不怕
he was afraid and you weren't.
寇克舰长？
Captain Kirk?
- 我是寇克 - 我是史波克
- Kirk here. - Spock here.
您能来一下传送室吗？
Would you come to the transporter room?
我想我们已经找到解决方法了
we think we may have found an answer.
就来
Coming.
什么办法？
What is it?
我们找到了让传送器工作的办法，先生
We found a way to get the transporter working, sir.
我们附加了一些旁路和主回路
We've attached some bypass and leader circuits
进行差额补偿，直接连接至脉冲引擎
to compensate for the difference, tied directly into the impulse engines.
- 是啊 - 这样速率平衡
- Yes. - There shouldn't be
不会超过5个点的误差
more than a five-point variation in the velocity balance.
建议我们先传送这个动物试一下
I suggest we send the animal through.
- 舰长？ - 是的，是的，就这么办
- Captain? - Yes, yes, go ahead.
我会尽可能地抓住它的颈背，控制住它
I'll grab him by the scruff of the neck and hold him as long as I can.
- 不要伤害它 - 很快就好，而且不会疼的
- Don't hurt him. - It's painless and quick.
它会丧失几分钟意识
The animal will be unconscious for only a few minutes.
如果不奏效，我也不知道该怎样了
If this doesn't work, I don't know what will.
传送
Energize.
逆转
Reverse.
对它们来说，融合所造成的冲击
The shock of putting him back together
似乎太大了
seems to have been too much for him.
它死了，吉姆
He's dead, Jim.
舰长日志，星历1673.1
Captain's log, stardate 1673.1.
记录者：史波克大副
Entry made by Second Officer Spock.
寇克舰长仍指挥着这艘星舰
Captain Kirk retains command of this vessel,
但他的意志力正在迅速衰退
but his force of will rapidly fading.
外遣队情况危急
Condition of landing party, critical.
传送器仍在抢修
Transporter unit still under repair.
全面尸检，抓紧
Autopsy in depth. Hurry.
我也不确定，但那动物可能是死于某种冲击
Oh, I don't know. The animal could've died of some kind of shock.
- 头一次我同意你的观点，医生
- 我只是说“可能”，史波克先生
- For once, I agree with you, doctor. - I said could have, Mr. Spock.
在得到验尸报告前我们还无法确定
We won't know until we get a full postmortem.
就算没有验尸报告也能确认那动物极度恐慌
No autopsy is necessary to know that the animal was terrified, confused.
它先是被分离成两个个体，然后又突然合体
It was split into two halves and suddenly thrust back together again.
莫名的恐惧引发了强力冲击
Thus, shock, induced by blind terror.
对，没错，很可能是这样
Yes, yes, that sounds likely.
它无法理解那种恐惧，但你可以
It couldn't understand. You can.
你的智慧能化解恐惧
You have your intelligence controlling your fear.
准备好传送室
Get the Transporter Room ready.
“可能、也许、或者”，这些都只是猜测
"Could be, if, maybe." All guesswork so far, just theory.
吉姆，为什么不给我点时间验下尸
Jim, why don't you give me a chance to do an autopsy
让史波克再检查一下传送器的电路呢
and let Spock check out the transporter circuits again.
你说得也有道理，也许我们应该再检查一下
That sounds reasonable. We should double-check everything.
你是不是忘了什么事情，舰长？
Aren't you forgetting something, captain?
- 不，我不觉得我忘… - 你的外遣队还在下面
- No, I don't think I for-- - Your men on the planet's surface.
他们还能坚持多久？
How much time do they have left?
是啊，我的船员还在下面
Yes, that's right, the men.
我们必须冒这个险，老骨头，他们的生命…
We have to take the chance, Bones. Their lives--
吉姆，假设那生物并不是因为刺激而死
Suppose it wasn't shock, Jim.
而是因为传送器的异常运作而死
Suppose death was caused by a transporter malfunction.
那你也会死
Then you'd die.
无论如何，他们都会死
They'd die anyway.
但是吉姆，你不能拿你的生命冒险
Jim, you can't risk your life on a theory.
被分离成两半的感觉我明白，医生
Being split in two halves is no theory with me, doctor.
我是人类，同时也是瓦肯外星人
I have a human half, you see, as well as an alien half
他们从未停止过斗争
submerged, constantly at war with each other.
这是我的切身感受，医生
Personal experience, doctor.
而我能活下来，是因为我的智慧战胜了它们
I survive it because my intelligence wins out over both,
使他们彼此共存
makes them live together.
你的智慧也会让你活下来的
Your intelligence would enable you to survive as well.
帮帮我
Help me.
帮我做个决定吧
Somebody make the decision.
你这是在放弃决策权吗，舰长？
Are you relinquishing your command, captain?
不
No.
不是的
No, I'm not.
那么我们就不能帮你下决定了，吉姆
Well then, we can't help you, Jim.
决策权在你手中
The decision is yours.
史波克先生，准备好传送室
Mr. Spock, ready the transporter room.
老骨头…
Bones...
…继续验尸
...continue the autopsy.
寇克舰长，我和苏鲁取得了联系
Captain Kirk, I have a tie in with Sulu now.
我是寇克
Kirk here.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk,
是我，苏鲁
Sulu here.
零下117度
117 below.
快坚持不住了
Can't last much longer.
看不清楚，医生
Can't see clearly, doctor,
无法…看清…指示器…内容
to read top indicator.
可能，寒冷…
Think the cold...
…使通讯器…失灵
...penetrating communicator.
两名队员…
Two men...
…丧失意识
...unconscious.
没时间了
No time.
没…
No...
坚持不住了
Can't wait.
没时间了
No time.
苏鲁先生
Mr. Sulu.
不能再等了
Can't wait.
不能让他们这么牺牲
Can't let them die.
你要怎么做？
What are you gonna do?
传送出去，我们都去
Go through the transporter, both of us.
没法阻止你了吗？
There's nothing I can do to stop you?
我必须这么做
It's what I have to do.
是我必须做的，也是我们必须做的
It's what I have to do, what we have to do.
我不会再反抗你了
I won't fight you anymore.
我感到很虚弱
I feel so weak.
我希望能快点结束这一切
I'll be glad when this is over.
贾尼丝，你好
Janice, hello.
- 舰长，我… - 文书，我欠你个解释
- Captain, I-- - Yeoman, I owe you an explanation.
- 不 - 是的，我应该解释一下
- No. - Yes, I do.
传送器运作异常，把我的人格分离并制造了一个复制品
The transporter malfunctioned, divided me, created a duplicate.
去你舱室的那个是我的阴暗面
The animal part of me came to your cabin.
他甚至把我抓伤了，为了让我们看起来更相似
He even scratched me, to make us look more alike.
我很高兴能向你解释清楚
I'd like the chance to explain it to you.
我等会再去你的舱室，不介意吧？
You don't mind if I come to your cabin later?
不介意，长官
No, sir.
到舰桥
Bridge.
- 我们和苏鲁先生失去了联系，长官 - 准备离开轨道，法瑞尔
- No word from Mr. Sulu, sir. - Prepare to leave orbit, Mr. Farrell.
- 怎么了？ - 舰长…
- Well? - Captain--
这是命令，法瑞尔
I gave you an order, Mr. Farrell.
- 那他们… - 我们救不了他们
- But what about--? - They can't be saved.
- 准备离开轨道 - 是的，长官
- Prepare to leave orbit. - Yes, sir.
- 我们本来不是打算… - 我改变了主意
- But I thought we planned-- - I've changed my mind.
回你的工作岗位去，史波克先生
Go back to your station, Mr. Spock.
- 抓住他，他是冒充的 - 不
- Grab him. He's the impostor. - No.
麦考伊，他骗了你
McCoy, he's fooled you.
他攻击了他
He attacked him.
史波克先生，你应该能分辨真伪
Mr. Spock, you know who I am. You know what that is.
史波克先生，到底是哪个？我们该怎么办？
Mr. Spock, which one? What do we do?
我们让舰长来处理
We'll let the captain handle this.
我才是舰长
I'm the captain.
这不是显而易见吗？看看他的脸
Isn't that obvious? Look at his face.
看看那些抓痕，他正试图掩藏起来
Remember the scratches? Look how he's tried to hide them.
他想让你们认为他才是舰长
He wants you to think that he's Captain Kirk.
你知道我是谁
You know who I am.
是的，我知道
Yes, I know.
你想杀了我，对吧？
You wanna kill me, don't you?
法瑞尔，詹姆士，抓住他，他会毁了星舰的
Farrell, James, grab him. He'll destroy the ship.
我才是舰长！你们还不明白吗？我才是真的舰长！
I'm the captain! Don't you understand? I'm captain of this ship!
这是我的星舰！我的！这是我的！
It's my ship! My ship! It’s mine!
我会杀了你
I'll kill you.
失去了对方，我们还能活下去吗？
Can half a man live?
再往前一步，我就杀了你
Take another step, you'll die.
那你也一样会死
Then we'll both die.
不要这样
Please.
我不想杀你，别逼我
I don't want to. Don't make me.
别逼我
Don't make me.
我不想回去
I don't wanna go back.
求你了
Please.
我想活下去
I wanna live.
你会活下去的
You will.
我们都会活下去的
Both of us.
我想活下去
I wanna live.
把他抱紧，舰长
You'll have to hold onto him, captain.
- 史波克先生 - 舰长
- Mr. Spock. - Captain.
如果失败了…
If this doesn't work...
我明白，舰长
Understood, captain.
史波克先生？
Mr. Spock?
准备好了
Ready.
史波克先生？
Well, Mr. Spock?
吉姆？
Jim?
赶紧把外遣队弄上来
Get those men aboard fast.
马上，舰长
Right away, captain.
冻伤很严重，但我想他们会没事的
Severe exposure, frostbite, but I think they'll make it.
你感觉如何，吉姆？
How do you feel, Jim?
感觉如何？
How?
我看到了自己那不为人知的一面
I've seen a part of myself no man should ever see.
状况报告，绿色
Status report green.
- 所有部门准备就绪，长官 - 很好
- All sections report ready, sir. - Good.
史波克先生，谢谢
Thank you, Mr. Spock,
来自我们两个的谢意
from both of us.
需要传达给船员吗，长官？
Shall I pass that on to the crew, sir?
他已经回去了，忘了他吧
The impostor's back where he belongs. Let's forget him.
舰长
Captain,
那个冒名者向我解释发生了什么事
the impostor told me what happened, who he really was.
我想说…
And I’d just like to say that...
嗯，那个，我是想说…
Well, sir, what I’d like to say is that--
谢谢你，文书
Thank you, yeoman.
那个冒名者有一些有趣的特质
The impostor had some interesting qualities,
不是吗，文书？
wouldn't you say, yeoman?
我是舰长
This is the captain speaking.
领航员，修正好航向
Navigator, set in course correction.
舵手，让星舰稳速前进
Helmsman, steady as she goes.
本集结束
谢谢观赏